<!-- So the language that I wrote is used by throwing in special characters in place of html tags that are
easier for the SME's to understand and use. I tried many different ways to google an EML but couldn't find
any examples so I tried my best to interperet what you were looking for. Certain characters, it is specified,
need a closer to indicate the ending of the desired change. Below are the characters and their functions:
/+ - This is a title, needs a closer
/$ - This is a line break (new line) or the enter key
/@ - This makes the font bold, needs a closer
/! - This puts the text in italics, needs a closer
/# - This is slightly large bold text, smaller than a title but bigger than small text, needs a closer
/- - This is a bullet point
/lt - This is the < character
/gt - This is the > character
/^ - This will add an apostrophe
/% - This is a teb character
/= - This is the Ampersand character
\\\\ -  This is a backslash character

I filled the DB with  the New Brunswick driver manual content because there wasn't any instruction as to what type of content
it should be.
-->
<xml>
    <course>
        <name>Driving Course</name>
        <code>101</code>
        <unit>
            <title>1</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+Licensing of Drivers/+
                    /$ /#1.1 Types of Licenses/#
                    /$/@/!Class 1/!/@
                    /$
                    /$/- Applicant must be at least 18 years of age.
                    /$/- Applicant must meet medical standards before written test.
                    /$/- Must pass vision screening (20/30 best eye; 20/50 weakest eye).
                    /$/- Must pass written tests (basic - sign - supplementary).
                    /$/- Must pass road test in a mechanically fit vehicle supplied by
                    applicant that is included in the Class. Normally this will be a
                    tractor-trailer combination. There are limited exceptions: (1)
                    straight truck with flatbed trailer over 4,500 kg. gross vehicle
                    mass; (2) straight truck with pole trailer; (3) truck used for
                    towing mobile homes. These exceptions will be class 1 with
                    Restriction 10 (not valid for tractor trailer).
                    /$
                    /$/@Explanation/@
                    /$
                    /$The Class 1 licence permits the holder to operate:
                    /$/- Any motor vehicle which the holder of a Class 2, 3, 4 or 5 licence may operate.
                    /$/- Any truck tractor.
                    /$/- Any truck tractor towing a semi-trailer.
                    /$/- Any truck tractor towing a semi-trailer and a trailer.
                    /$/- Any truck tractor towing a trailer equipped with air brakes.
                    /$/- Any truck towing a trailer equipped with air brakes.
                    /$/- Must have air brake endorsement when driving any vehicle with air brakes and any vehicle towing a trailer with air brakes.
                    /$
                    /$/@/!Class 3/!/@
                    /$
                    /$/- Applicant must be at least 18 years of age.
                    /$/- Applicant must meet medical standards before written test.
                    /$/- Must pass vision screening (20/30 best eye; 20/50 weakest eye).
                    /$/- Must pass written tests (basic - signs - supplementary test).
                    /$/- Must pass road test in mechanically fit vehicle supplied by applicant that is included in this Class.
                    /$
                    /$/@Explanation/@
                    /$
                    /$The Class 3 licence permits the holder to operate:
                    /$/- Any motor vehicle which the holder of a Class 5 licence may operate.
                    /$/- Any two-axled motor vehicle towing a towed vehicle, the towed vehicle being registered for over 4,500 kg. gross vehicle mass
                    but not equipped with air brakes.
                    /$/- Any motor vehicle with three or more axles.
                    /$/- Any motor vehicle with three or more axles, towing a towed vehicle not equipped with air brakes.
                    /$
                    /$/@/!Class 5/!/@
                    /$
                    /$/- Applicant must be at least 18 years of age.
                    /$/- Must pass vision screening (20/40 best eye).
                    /$/- Must pass road test in mechanically fit vehicle supplied by the applicant that is included in this Class.
                    /$
                    /$Explanation
                    /$
                    /$Class 5 licence permits the holder to operate:
                    /$/- Any two-axled motor vehicle, except taxi, ambulance, or bus.
                    /$/- Any three-axled motor home.
                    /$/- Any three axled motor vehicle, other than a truck, of a type designed for use in the construction, maintenance and repair of
                    highways, whether or not the vehicle is to be so used.
                    /$/- Any towed vehicle which is registered up to and including 4,500 kg. gross vehicle mass behind a motor vehicle or motor home.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+Licensing of Drivers/+
                    /$ /#1.2 List of Possible Endorsements/#
                    /$
                    /$/-A  Valid for all motorcycles
                    /$/-B  Valid for school buses
                    /$/-C  Valid for school bus and motorcycle
                    /$/-D  Valid for motorcycles up to and including 550 ccs
                    /$/-E  Valid for air brake (plastic licence)
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>3</number>
                <content>/+Licensing of Drivers/+
                    /$ /#1.3 Examination for Learner’s Licence/#
                    /$
                    /$Before you, as a resident of New Brunswick, may obtain a learner’s
                    licence, you must pass an examination to determine if you meet
                    the required vision standards. You must also have an acceptable
                    knowledge of road signs, rules of the road and safe driving
                    practices. In addition, you must present one original or certified copy
                    of a valid passport, birth certificate, or court order to verify your name
                    and date of birth and two pieces of identification to verify your current
                    address. Please contact Service New Brunswick for a complete list
                    of acceptable documents. It may be a requirement for a parent or
                    guardian to accompany you to verify your address.
                    /$
                    /$You must have the written consent of a parent or guardian
                    before applying for a licence if you are less than 18 years of age.
                    A consent form is provided at the back of this book and must be
                    witnessed properly.
                    /$
                    /$This written consent may be withdrawn by the parent or guardian
                    at any time prior to age 18, by making written application to the
                    Registrar of Motor Vehicles who may then cancel the licence.
                    /$
                    /$/@Vision Test/@
                    /$
                    /$If it is found that you need visual correction in order
                    to drive safely, you will be advised accordingly and
                    no further testing can occur and a licence cannot
                    be issued to you until you obtain the necessary
                    correction. When a driver’s licence is issued, it will
                    display the appropriate restriction “Valid only while
                    licence holder is wearing proper visual correction”.
                    /$
                    /$/@Road Sign Recognition Test/@
                    /$
                    /$You will be given a written or oral examination on your ability to
                    recognize and understand the meaning of highway road signs. This
                    test consists of twenty (20) signs. To pass, you must correctly match
                    sixteen (16), with the exception of “stop”, “yield” and “school ahead”
                    which are mandatory.
                    /$
                    /$/@Rules Test/@
                    /$
                    /$You will be given a written or oral examination on the traffic laws
                    and rules for safe driving as contained in this book. The written
                    exam consists of twenty (20) multiple choice questions. To pass,
                    you must answer sixteen (16) correctly. Although this guide offers
                    measurements in both Metric and Imperial systems, the written test
                    refers only to the Metric system.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>4</number>
                <content>/+Licensing of Drivers/+
                    /$ /#1.4 Examination for Driver’s Licence/#
                    /$
                    /$Note: Appointments for testing can only be booked through Service
                    New Brunswick Teleservices (1-888-762-8600)
                    /$You must pass a driving examination to determine whether you are
                    qualified to operate a motor vehicle safely before you can be issued
                    a driver’s licence. These examinations are conducted by a Driver
                    Examiner who also indicates the areas of your driving which need
                    further improvement and stresses the importance of your attitude as a
                    determining factor in safe driving
                    /$
                    /$/@Driving Test/@
                    /$
                    /$This is an examination to test your actual driving skills and your ability
                    to operate a vehicle safely while abiding by the rules of the Motor
                    Vehicle Act. You must come to the examination office with a vehicle
                    that is in good mechanical condition, preferably the one which you
                    expect to operate after you obtain your driver’s licence. (You must
                    have the valid motor vehicle registration and insurance card to show
                    the Examiner upon request). As part of the road test, the vehicle will
                    be checked by the Examiner to ensure that it meets the standards set
                    out under the Motor Vehicle Act. The road test will not be conducted if
                    the vehicle is not in satisfactory mechanical condition.
                    /$
                    /$The driving test includes such operations as:
                    /$/- Stopping and starting, both on a level road and on a hill.
                    /$/- Changing gears in vehicles not having automatic transmissions, both on a level road and on a hill.
                    /$/- Making left and right turns.
                    /$/- Backing.
                    /$/- Following another vehicle properly.
                    /$/- Giving proper signals.
                    /$/- Parallel and/or angle parking.
                    /$/- Observing and complying with traffic control devices (signs, signals and pavement markings).
                    /$
                    /$The examination will be conducted over a course of at least 3 km,
                    and when possible, will be conducted in fairly dense traffic. The
                    exam also tests your ability to apply your knowledge of the rules of
                    the road, recognition of road signs, visual perception, etc.
                    /$
                    /$You may know every safe driving rule, may have adequate vision
                    and other physical abilities and may exhibit the most exemplary
                    attitude, but until you show your ability and skill in an actual
                    driving test, you have not proven that you are competent to
                    operate a motor vehicle safely upon the highway.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>5</number>
                <content>/+Licensing of Drivers/+
                    /$ /#1.5 How You May Lose Your Driving Privilege/#
                    /$
                    /$The Registrar MUST suspend your driving privileges for any of the following reasons:
                    /$/- When a total of ten points is assessed against your driving record (other than a newly licensed driver).
                    /$/- When a newly licensed driver loses all points credited to him/her.
                    /$/- Upon conviction for operating or permitting operation of a motor vehicle that is uninsured.
                    /$/- When any points are assessed against an unlicensed driver or a non-resident unlicensed driver.
                    /$/- A conviction for altering a licence.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
        <unit>
            <title>2</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+Registration of Vehicles/+
                    /$ /#2.1 Certificate of Registration/#
                    /$
                    /$The owner of every motor vehicle, trailer or semi-trailer, who intends to operate that vehicle
                    upon any highway in New Brunswick, must obtain registration for that vehicle by applying
                    to Service New Brunswick. The registration permit or a photocopy must be carried by the
                    driver while operating the vehicle.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+Registration of Vehicles/+
                    /$ /#2.2 Plates are Property of the Crown/#
                    /$
                    /$Plates and permits remain the property of the Crown and must be surrendered upon demand. Found plates should be delivered to
                    Service New Brunswick or forwarded to Motor Vehicle Branch, P. O. Box 6000, Fredericton, NB E3B 5H1.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>3</number>
                <content>/+Registration of Vehicles/+
                    /$ /#2.3 Plates Must Be Legible/#
                    /$
                    /$Licence plates must be securely fastened to the front and rear of the vehicle in such a position and
                    condition as to be clearly legible and the rear plate must be lighted at night.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>4</number>
                <content>/+Registration of Vehicles/+
                    /$ /#2.4 Owner Responsible for Plates/#
                    /$
                    /$You are responsible for the custody of licence plates or validation stickers issued to you for the current year and must immediately
                    notify Service New Brunswick when they are no longer in your possession. There is a nominal fee for replacing lost plates and stickers.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
        <unit>
            <title>3</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+Equipment/+
                    /$ /#3.1 Lights/#
                    /$
                    /$No person shall drive a vehicle on a highway at nighttime or any other time when there is not sufficient light to render clearly
                    discernible persons and vehicles on the highway at a distance of 150 meters (500 feet) unless the vehicle is equipped with and
                    class of vehicle so driven. displays lighted lamps and illuminating devices as required for the
                    /$
                    /$/@Headlamps/@
                    /$
                    /$Every motor vehicle, except a motorcycle or motor driven cycle, must have at least two headlights displaying white light. One must be attached to each side of the
                    vehicle not more than 140 centimetres (55 inches) from the ground and not less than 60 centimetres (24 inches). They must have an upper beam that clearly
                    shows ahead for 100 metres (330 feet) and a lower beam that shows 30 metres (100 feet).
                    /$
                    /$Lights must be dimmed within 150 metres (500 feet) of an approaching vehicle. When following another vehicle within 60 metres (200 feet) the lower
                    beam must be used except when in the act of passing. It is permissible for a vehicle to be equipped and operated with an auxiliary lamp or spot lamp providing
                    the total intensity does not exceed 300 candle power.
                    /$
                    /$/@Motor Cycle Lamps/@
                    /$
                    /$Every motorcycle must be equipped with at least one and not more than three head lamps displaying white light. The light must
                    be strong enough to reveal a person or vehicle at 100 metres (330 feet) when speed is 60 km (35 miles) per hour or more. The lamp
                    or lamps must be aimed so that the high intensity portion does not project higher than the level of the centre of the lamp at a
                    distance of 750 centimetres (25 feet).
                    /$
                    /$/@Rear Lamps/@
                    /$
                    /$Every motor vehicle, trailer, etc. and the last vehicle in a train of vehicles must have at least two red tail lights mounted one on
                    either side of the rear of the vehicle at a height of not more than 183 centimetres (72 inches) and not less than 38 centimetres (15
                    inches). This light must be visible from a distance of 150 metres (500 feet) to the rear. Every vehicle must be equipped with a
                    white light to illuminate the rear licence plate and make it clearly readable at a distance of 15 metres (50 feet).
                    /$
                    /$/@Rear Lamps/@
                    /$
                    /$Every bus or truck must have on the rear two red reflectors and one stop light
                    /$
                    /$Every commercial vehicle, semi-trailer or trailer 2 metres (80 inches) or more in width must have in addition to the above:
                    /$/- On the front, one amber clearance lamp on each side.
                    /$/- On the rear and as high as practical a red clearance lamp on each side.
                    /$/- On each side an amber reflector at or near the front and one red near the rear.
                    /$/- Mud flaps mounted immediately behind the rear wheels.
                    /$/- In the vehicle, three flares, electric lanterns or portable reflectors capable of reflecting red light for a distance of 150
                    metres (500 feet) under normal nighttime conditions. They must also carry two red cloth flags at least 30 centimetres (12
                    inches) square.
                    /$
                    /$/@Brake Lights/@
                    /$
                    /$Motor vehicles operated on a highway must be equipped with a red stop lamp or lamps. This lamp must be plainly visible and
                    understandable from a distance of 30 metres (100 feet) to the rear both during daylight and darkness.
                    /$
                    /$/@Signal Devices/@
                    /$
                    /$Any motor vehicle may be equipped with a lamp or lamps or mechanical signal devices capable of clearly indicating an
                    intention to turn either to the right or to the left, such signal devices being visible both from the front and the rear.
                    /$
                    /$A signal lamp or lamps indicating intention to turn must be visible during daylight and darkness from a distance of 30 metres (100
                    feet) both to the front and to the rear.
                    /$
                    /$/@Daytime Running Lights/@
                    /$
                    /$Beginning with the model year 1990 all new vehicles must be equipped with daytime running lights which activate
                    automatically. A vehicle using these lights is more easily seen by other motorists, pedestrians and cyclists.
                    /$
                    /$Older vehicles may be modified to produce automatic daytime running lights.
                    /$
                    /$If your vehicle is not equipped with daytime running lights, it is suggested that you use your headlights at all times.
                    /$
                    /$/@Daytime Running Lights/@
                    /$
                    /$It is suggested that all motor vehicles be equipped with a “stop” light. This light must be so constructed and placed where it will
                    give a red signal to the rear of the vehicle which is plainly visible in normal sunlight from a distance of 100 metres (330 feet). The stop
                    light may or may not be the same as the rear lamp unit.
                    /$
                    /$/@Daytime Running Lights/@
                    /$
                    /$When a vehicle is equipped with a switch permitting the parking and tail lights to flash, the flashing lights can be used when the
                    vehicle is parked on the highway or any portion thereof due to an emergency or under circumstances beyond the control of the driver.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+Equipment/+
                    /$ /#3.2 Brakes/#
                    /$
                    /$Every motor vehicle must be equipped with an adequate foot brake and an emergency brake in good working order.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>3</number>
                <content>/+Equipment/+
                    /$ /#3.3 Horn/#
                    /$
                    /$Every motor vehicle must be equipped with a horn in good working order that can be heard for a distance of not less than 60
                    metres (200 feet) but a horn must not emit an unreasonably loud or harsh sound or whistle. The horn should be sounded whenever
                    it is necessary to ensure safe operation of a vehicle or to give warning of the approach of a vehicle.
                    /$
                    /$Except for authorized emergency vehicles, no siren, whistle or bell is to be used.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>4</number>
                <content>/+Equipment/+
                    /$ /#3.4 Mirror/#
                    /$
                    /$Every motor vehicle must be equipped with a mirror so located as to reflect to the driver a view of the highway for a distance of
                    at least 60 metres (200 feet) to the rear of such vehicle. Portable door or fender mirrors are illegal when not towing trailer or other vehicle.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>5</number>
                <content>/+Equipment/+
                    /$ /#3.5 Windshields and Windows/#
                    /$
                    /$All windshields and windows must be kept clear of any signs, posters or other non-transparent material which obstruct the
                    driver’s clear view of the highway or any intersecting highway.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
        <unit>
            <title>4</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+Rules of the Road/+
                    /$ /#4.1 Collisions/#
                    /$
                    /$The driver of any vehicle involved in a collision causing death or injury to any person or property damage must stop at the scene of
                    the collision, give his/her name, address, the registration number of his/her vehicle along with the liability insurance card and show
                    his/her driver’s licence to the person struck or to occupants of any assistance to any injured person.
                    vehicle collided with or to a witness and shall render all reasonable
                    /$
                    /$/@First at the Scene/@
                    /$
                    /$Remember, handling the injured must be avoided unless there is added danger of being struck by oncoming motorists.
                    /$
                    /$/@Emergency Vehicles/@
                    /$
                    /$Upon the approach from either direction of any authorized emergency vehicle giving an audible signal by way of bell or
                    siren and visual by flashing red lights, the driver of all vehicles must immediately drive to the right hand curb and must stop and
                    remain stopped until the emergency vehicle has passed, unless otherwise directed by a peace officer.
                    /$
                    /$/@Reporting Collisions/@
                    /$
                    /$Collisions resulting in death or injury to any person, or total property damage to an apparent extent of $1,000.00 or more
                    must be reported immediately to the nearest office of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police or if in a town or city, to a member of
                    the local police.
                    /$
                    /$Collision reports must be forwarded to the Registrar of Motor Vehicles within 24 hours.
                    /$
                    /$The Registrar of Motor Vehicles is authorized to suspend the operating privileges of any person failing to report a collision.
                    /$
                    /$/@Financial Responsibility/@
                    /$
                    /$A driver involved in a collision in which a person is injured, even slightly, or killed, or when the total property damage amounts
                    to $1,000.00 or more, must be able to prove his/her financial responsibility at the time of the collision. The accepted proof is a
                    New Brunswick Liability Insurance Card, issued by an authorized insurance company, showing that public liability and property
                    damage coverage has been issued on behalf of the driver or the owner of the vehicle.
                    /$
                    /$The Registrar, on receipt of a collision report that does not show the owner or driver has financial responsibility, must suspend the
                    motor vehicle privileges of the owner and operator and cancel all registrations and licence against both the owner and driver. Before
                    reinstatement can be made, proof of financial responsibility for the future must be filed with the Registrar of Motor Vehicles.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+Rules of the Road/+
                    /$ /#4.2 Speed Restrictions/#
                    /$
                    /$Where no speed hazard exists that require lower speed, the speed limits on provincial streets and highways are:
                    /$/- 50 km (30 miles) per hour in any urban district
                    /$/- 80 km (50 miles) per hour in other locations or as otherwise posted.
                    /$
                    /$This means that a driver apprehended at speeds in excess of those noted above is committing an offence.
                    /$
                    /$/#OTHER SPEED LIMITS MAY BE INDICATED FOR CERTAIN SECTIONS OF THE HIGHWAYS BY SIGNS ERECTED BY ORDER OF THE TRAFFIC AUTHORITY AND
                    THESE POSTED LIMITS MAY NOT BE EXCEEDED./#
                    /$
                    /$No person is permitted to operate a vehicle upon any highway at such a speed as to endanger the life, limb or property of any
                    person, including his/her own.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>3</number>
                <content>/+Rules of the Road/+
                    /$ /#4.3 Slow Drivers/#
                    /$
                    /$It is an offence under the Act for any person to drive at such a slow speed as to block the normal and reasonable movement of traffic,
                    except when reduced speed is necessary for safe operation.
                    /$
                    /$Should a driver find it necessary to drive at a slow speed on the open highway, he/she must always keep well to the right and
                    occasionally look back to see if traffic is being slowed down and if so, the driver must pull off the road and give the traffic a chance to pass.
                    /$
                    /$To delay traffic is a discourteous and illegal act and greatly increases the chance of a collision. The “road hog” is a menace
                    almost as great as those who drive too fast for conditions.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>4</number>
                <content>/+Rules of the Road/+
                    /$ /#4.4 Overtaking/#
                    /$
                    /$Except when overtaking and where passing on the right is permitted, the driver of an overtaken vehicle must move to the
                    right in favour of the overtaking vehicle upon hearing audible signal and shall not increase the speed of his/her vehicle until
                    completely passed by the overtaking vehicle.
                    /$
                    /$It is an offence to pass another vehicle on the right except when:
                    /$/- overtaking a vehicle making a left turn or signalling a left turn
                    /$/- on a one way street
                    /$/- on streets and highways marked for multi-lanes going in the same direction
                    /$
                    /$Extreme care should be taken in the above situations because other drivers may swerve over to the right without warning. /@You
                    must not drive off the roadway onto the shoulder to pass another vehicle./@
                    /$
                    /$It is unlawful for a vehicle to be driven to the left side of the roadway under the following circumstances:
                    /$/- When approaching the crest of a grade or upon a curve in the highway where the driver’s view is obstructed within such
                    distance as to create a hazard in the event another vehicle might approach from the opposite direction
                    /$/- When approaching within 30 metres (100 feet) of or crossing any intersection or railroad grade crossing; or
                    /$/- When the view is obstructed upon approaching within 30 metres (100 feet) of any bridge, viaduct or tunnel).
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>5</number>
                <content>/+Rules of the Road/+
                    /$ /#4.5 Blind Spots/#
                    /$
                    /$All vehicles have a “blind spot” in the right and left rear corners. Your rear view mirror will not show a car in the lane next to
                    yours when its front bumper is about even with or ahead of your rear bumper. If you rely only upon your inside mirror and
                    turn into another lane without looking over your shoulder you could collide with a vehicle travelling in your blind spot.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>6</number>
                <content>/+Rules of the Road/+
                    /$ /#4.6 Signalling/#
                    /$
                    /$The law requires you to signal other drivers of your intention to stop or decrease the speed of your vehicle, turn to the left or the
                    right, change from one lane of traffic to another lane of traffic, leave the roadway or set your vehicle in motion from a parked position
                    /$
                    /$If a vehicle is so constructed or loaded as to prevent the hand and arm signal from being visible, or if any portion of the vehicle or the
                    load on the vehicle extends more than 60 centimetres (24 inches) to the left of the centre of the vehicle’s steering wheel, the signal
                    must be given by a mechanical or electrical signalling device.
                    /$
                    /$Signals must be given by signalling devices, stop light or hand and arm. Give correct signals well in advance and in such a way as to
                    be plainly visible to other drivers. Check your signalling devices frequently to ensure that they are working properly.
                    /$
                    /$All signals shall be given at least 30 metres (100 feet) before making a turn.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
    </course>
    <course>
        <name>Boating Course</name>
        <code>102</code>
        <unit>
            <title>1</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+Before Getting Underway/+
                    /$ /#1.1 Commonly Used Terms/#
                    /$
                    /$/@Vessel:/@ A ship, pleasure craft, or non-pleasure craft capable of being used as a means of transportation on water
                    /$/@Pleasure Craft:/@ A vessel that is used only for pleasure or recreational activities, such as fishing or water sports,
                    and does not carry paid passengers
                    /$/@Non-Pleasure Craft:/@ A small commercial vessel that carries goods or passengers (people who have paid a fee to be transported),
                    a workboat, a commercial fishing vessel, etc.
                    /$/@Boat:/@ A pleasure craft
                    /$/@Power-Driven Vessel:/@ Any vessel that is propelled by a motor or machinery
                    /$/@Sailing Vessel:/@ Any vessel that is propelled only by wind in its sails and not by a motor or machinery
                    /$/@Operate:/@ To control the speed and course of a pleasure craft
                    /$/@Operator:/@ The person in control of the speed and course of a pleasure craft
                    /$/@Design Waterline:/@ The waterline when a pleasure craft is at its maximum recommended gross load capacity
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+Before Getting Underway/+
                    /$ /#1.2 Parts of a Boat From a Side View/#
                    /$
                    /$/@Bow:/@ Front of a Vessel
                    /$/@Cleat:/@ Metal fitting on which a rope can be fastened
                    /$/@Gunwhale:/@ Upper edge of vessel’s side (generally pronounced gunnel)
                    /$/@Hull:/@ Body of a Vessel
                    /$/@Port:/@ Left side of a Vessel
                    /$/@Propeller:/@ Rotates and powers a boat forward or backward
                    /$/@Starboard:/@ Right side of a Vessel
                    /$/@Stern:/@ Rear of a Vessel
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>3</number>
                <content>/+Before Getting Underway/+
                    /$ /#1.3 Parts of a Boat From a Front View/#
                    /$
                    /$/@Beam:/@ Maximum width of a boat
                    /$/@Freeboard:/@ Distance from water to lowest point of the boat where water could come on board
                    /$/@Draft:/@ Depth of water needed to float a boat
                    /$/@Keel:/@ Main centreline (backbone) of a boat or the extension of hull that increases stability in the water
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>4</number>
                <content>/+Before Getting Underway/+
                    /$ /#1.4 Displacement Hulls/#
                    /$
                    /$There are two basic types of boat hulls—displacement and planing.
                    /$
                    /$Boats with displacement hulls move through the water by pushing the water aside and are designed to cut through
                    the water with very little propulsion.
                    /$/- If you lower a boat into the water, some of the water moves out of the way to adjust for the boat. If you could
                    weigh that displaced water, you would find it equals the weight of the boat. That weight is the boat’s displacement.
                    /$/- Boats with displacement hulls are limited to slower speeds.
                    /$/- A round-bottomed hull shape acts as a displacement hull. Most large cruisers and most sailboats have displacement
                    hulls, allowing them to travel more smoothly through the water.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>5</number>
                <content>/+Before Getting Underway/+
                    /$ /#1.5 Planing Hulls/#
                    /$
                    /$Boats with planing hulls are designed to rise up and glide on top of the water when enough power is supplied. These
                    boats may operate like displacement hulls when at rest or at slow speeds but climb toward the surface of the water as
                    they move faster.
                    /$
                    /$/- Boats with planing hulls can skim along at high speed, riding almost on top of the water rather than pushing it aside.
                    /$/- Flat-bottomed and vee-bottomed hull shapes act as planing hulls. Most small power-driven boats, including personal
                    watercraft (PWCs), and some small sailboats have planing hulls, allowing them to travel more rapidly across the water.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>6</number>
                <content>/+Before Getting Underway/+
                    /$ /#1.6 How Planing Hulls Operate/#
                    /$
                    /$/@Displacement Mode:/@ A planing hull, when operated at very slow speeds, will cut through the water like a displacement hull.
                    /$/@Plowing Mode:/@ As speed increases, a planing hull will have a raised bow, reducing the operator’s vision and throwing a very
                    large wake. Avoid maintaining a speed that puts your boat in plowing mode.
                    /$/@Planing Mode:/@ Your boat is in planing mode when enough power is applied so that the hull glides on top of the water.
                    Different boats reach planing mode at different speeds.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
        <unit>
            <title>2</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+Mandatory Safety Equipment/+
                    /$ /#2.1 Flotation Devices/#
                    /$
                    /$There are two main types of flotation devices.
                    /$
                    /$/@Lifejackets/@ will turn most unconscious persons face up in the water. Standard lifejackets are keyhole-style flotation devices
                    that are approved for use on all pleasure craft.
                    /$/@Personal Flotation Devices (PFDs)/@ are designed to be more comfortable to wear than lifejackets, but they may not turn an
                    unconscious person face up in the water.
                    /$
                    /$To comply with the Small Vessel Regulations, all pleasure craft must be equipped with enough Canadian-approved lifejackets or PFDs
                    for everyone on board. Each lifejacket or PFD must have enough buoyancy, be in good condition, and very importantly, be readily
                    accessible! Readily accessible means you must be able to put the flotation device on in a reasonable amount of time in an emergency
                    (vessel sinking, on fire, etc.). Flotation devices should not be stowed in plastic bags or in locked or closed compartments, and they
                    should not have other gear stowed on top of them.
                    /$
                    /$Flotation devices also must be the proper size for the intended wearer. Sizing for flotation devices is based on the person’s weight
                    and chest size. The only exceptions to this requirement are:
                    /$/- A person with a chest size in excess of 140 cm
                    /$/- A child weighing less than 9 kg (20 lbs)
                    /$
                    /$Pleasure craft operators should ask everyone on their boat to wear a flotation device whenever on the water, particularly in smaller
                    boats. Although you can choose between lifejackets and PFDs, keep in mind that lifejackets offer better protection. /@Flotation devices
                    can save lives, but only if they are worn!/@
                    /$
                    /$An emergency situation (rough water, rapid onset of bad weather, or dangerous boating traffic) can occur suddenly—leaving little or
                    no time to put on lifejackets or PFDs. Lifejackets and PFDs are very difficult to put on once you are in the water. Be a smart boater,
                    and have everyone on board your boat wear a lifejacket or PFD at all times.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+Mandatory Safety Equipment/+
                    /$ /#2.2 Personal Flotation Devices/#
                    /$
                    /$Approved personal flotation devices (PFDs) may be used instead of lifejackets on all pleasure craft, regardless of length. This includes
                    inherently buoyant and inflatable PFDs.
                    /$
                    /$/- PFDs are designed to be more comfortable than lifejackets. This is a benefit when you plan to wear a flotation device constantly while boating.
                    /$/- Not all PFDs are red, orange, or yellow. It is a good idea to choose one of these colours, however, so that you are more visible when in the water.
                    /$/- PFDs usually offer less flotation than lifejackets and have a limited capability to turn you on your back if you fall in the water.
                    /$/- Some PFDs provide thermal protection against hypothermia.
                    /$/- All adult-size inherently buoyant PFDs are designed to be worn by persons who weigh more than 41 kg (90 lbs). They range in size from XXS to XXXL.
                    /$
                    /$Choose a PFD based on what you will be doing while wearing it.
                    /$
                    /$/- PFDs that have three or more chest belts will be more secure if you will be operating at high speeds.
                    /$/- PFDs with thermal protection are a good choice if you will be boating in water that is less than 15°C.
                    /$/- PFDs are available for specific activities, including canoeing, kayaking, sailboarding, and water skiing.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>3</number>
                <content>/+Mandatory Safety Equipment/+
                    /$ /#2.3 Manual Propelling Devices and Anchors/#
                    /$
                    /$The Small Vessel Regulations require certain pleasure craft to carry on board a manual propelling device or an anchor.
                    /$/- Pleasure craft up to 9 metres (29.5 feet) in length, including PWCs, are required to carry either a manual propelling device or an anchor on board.
                    PWCs are exempt from this requirement if everyone on board is wearing a lifejacket or PFD.
                    /$/- Pleasure craft over 9 metres (29.5 feet) in length must have an anchor on board.
                    /$
                    /$/#Manual Propelling Devices/#
                    /$
                    /$Manual propelling devices can be:
                    /$/- Oars /!/@or…/@/!
                    /$/- Paddles /!/@or…/@/!
                    /$/- Rudders on small open sailboats /!/@or…/@/!
                    /$/- Anything else that can be operated with hands or feet to propel a pleasure craft.
                    /$
                    /$/#Anchors/#
                    /$
                    /$An anchor must have a line of cable, rope, or galvanized chain attached.
                    /$
                    /$The required length of the line depends on the length and type of pleasure craft you are operating.
                    /$/- Sailboats and powerboats up to 9 metres (29.5 feet) in length and PWCs must have at least 15 metres (49.2 feet) of cable, rope, or chain.
                    /$/- Sailboats and powerboats over 9 metres and up to 12 metres (29.5 feet to 39.4 feet) in length must have at least 30 metres (98.4 feet) of cable, rope, or chain.
                    /$/- Sailboats and powerboats over 12 metres (39.4 feet) in length must have at least 50 metres (164 feet) of cable, rope, or chain.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>4</number>
                <content>/+Mandatory Safety Equipment/+
                    /$ /#2.4 Bailers and Bilge Pumps/#
                    /$
                    /$To be able to remove water from the hull, the Small Vessel Regulations require you to carry a manual bilge pump. If your boat is not more than 9 metres
                    (29.5 feet) long, you may carry a bailer instead of a pump. PWCs may carry a manual bilge pump or a bailer.
                    /$/- If you have a manual bilge pump, the pump and hose must be long enough that water can be pumped from the bilge space of the boat over the side of the boat.
                    /$/- If you have a bailer, the bailer should be made of plastic or metal, have an opening of at least 65 square centimetres (10 square inches), and be able to
                    hold at least 750 millilitres (0.2 gallons).
                    /$
                    /$/#Non-Manual Bilge Pumps/#
                    /$
                    /$Some pleasure craft are equipped with non-manual bilge pumps and water level detection systems.
                    /$
                    /$These bilge pumps must be fitted with or accompanied by pipes or a hose long enough that water
                    can be pumped from the bilge space of the boat over the side of the boat.
                    /$
                    /$Pleasure craft operators should make sure that:
                    /$/- Bilge pumping systems are functioning as intended.
                    /$/- Bilge pumping systems can be accessed easily for routine maintenance.
                    /$/- There is a way to detect water levels in all bilges and spaces that are below the waterline and cannot be seen from the helm.
                    /$/- Each bilge water level indicator has a light.
                    /$/- All bilge water level indicators are connected to a single alarm that can be heard.
                    /$/- Bilge pumping and bilge alarm systems are tested routinely.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>5</number>
                <content>/+Mandatory Safety Equipment/+
                    /$ /#2.5 Fire Fighting Equipment/#
                    /$
                    /$The type and length of your pleasure craft determines what types of fire-fighting equipment, if any, you are required to carry on board.
                    Fire-fighting equipment includes axes, fire buckets, and fire extinguishers.
                    /$
                    /$/#Axes/#
                    /$
                    /$Here are the requirements for axes from the Small Vessel Regulations.
                    /$
                    /$/- Pleasure craft up to 12 metres (39.4 feet) in length are not required to carry an axe on board.
                    /$/- Pleasure craft that are more than 12 metres in length up to 24 metres (39.4 feet to 78.7 feet) in length are required to carry one axe.
                    /$
                    /$The preferred type of axe is a fireman’s axe that has a short handle and a head with a spike and a cutting edge. On pleasure craft, any
                    type of axe is acceptable, including a hatchet.
                    /$
                    /$Store axes in a readily accessible area. In an emergency, an axe can be used to cut a tow line.
                    /$
                    /$/#Fire Buckets/#
                    /$
                    /$Fire buckets are carried on board pleasure craft to fight fires.
                    /$
                    /$Fire buckets must:
                    /$/- Be painted red /!/@and…/@/!
                    /$/- Have a capacity of at least 10 litres /!/@and…/@/!
                    /$/- Be made of metal with a round bottom and a hole in the centre  /!/@and…/@/!
                    /$/- Have an attached lanyard that is long enough to reach the water from the location where the bucket is stored.
                    /$
                    /$The requirements for fire buckets are found in the Small Vessel Regulations and depend on the length of your pleasure craft:
                    /$/- Pleasure craft up to 12 metres (39.4 feet) in length are not required to carry a fire bucket on board.
                    /$/- Pleasure craft that are more than 12 metres in length up to 24 metres (39.4 feet to 78.7 feet) in length are required to carry two fire buckets.
                    /$
                    /$/#Fire Buckets/#
                    /$
                    /$Extinguishers are classified by letters and numbers. The numbers indicate the size of fire the extinguisher will put out compared to other
                    extinguishers. For example, a 10B:C extinguisher contains more chemicals and will put out a larger fire than a 5B:C extinguisher. The letters
                    indicate the types of fires the extinguisher will put out.
                    /$
                    /$/- Class A fires are of combustible solids like wood.
                    /$/- Class B fires are of flammable liquids like gasoline or oil.
                    /$/- Class C fires are electrical fires.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
        <unit>
            <title>3</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+Safe Navigation on the Water/+
                    /$ /#3.1 Rules for Encoutering Other Vessels/#
                    /$
                    /$There are rules that every operator must follow when encountering other vessels.
                    /$
                    /$Two terms help explain these rules.
                    /$/- /@Give-way vessel:/@ The vessel that is required to take early and substantial
                    action to keep out of the way of other vessels by stopping, slowing down, or changing
                    course. Avoid crossing in front of other vessels. Any change of course and/or speed
                    should be large enough to be readily apparent to another vessel. (A series of small changes should be avoided.)
                    /$/- /@Stand-on vessel:/@ The vessel that must maintain its course and speed unless it becomes apparent that the
                    give-way vessel is not taking appropriate action. If you must take action, do not turn toward the give-way vessel
                    or cross in front of it.
                    /$
                    /$The action a vessel operator should take when encountering another vessel depends on the answers to two questions.
                    /$
                    /$/@How are the two vessels propelled?/@
                    /$/- Two power-driven vessels
                    /$/- Two sailing vessels
                    /$/- A power-driven vessel and a sailing vessel
                    /$
                    /$/@How are the two vessels approaching one another?/@
                    /$/- Meeting head-on: A vessel operator sees another vessel ahead or nearly ahead
                    /$/- Paths that cross: Two vessels are on crossing paths so as to involve risk of collision
                    /$/- Overtaking: A vessel is coming upon another vessel from behind or nearly behind the other vessel
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+Safe Navigation on the Water/+
                    /$ /#3.2 Exceptions to the Navigation Rules/#
                    /$
                    /$The rules that follow cover most of the situations you will encounter as a pleasure craft operator. However, be
                    aware that there are exceptions to the rules. For example, if you approach a vessel that has less manoeuvrability
                    than your vessel, the other vessel will usually be the stand-on vessel.
                    /$
                    /$Every operator is responsible for avoiding a collision. In complying with the navigation rules, operators must
                    consider all dangers of navigation; risk of collisions; and any special conditions, including the limitations of the
                    boats involved. These considerations may make a departure from the navigation rules necessary to avoid immediate danger.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>3</number>
                <content>/+Safe Navigation on the Water/+
                    /$ /#3.3 Power-Driven Vessel Encountering Power-Driven Vessel/#
                    /$
                    /$The actions you must take when encountering another vessel are found in the Collision Regulations.
                    /$
                    /$/@Meeting Head-On:/@ Neither vessel is the stand-on vessel. Both vessels should turn to starboard (the right).
                    /$
                    /$/@Paths That Cross:/@ The vessel on the operator’s port (left) is the give-way vessel. The vessel on the operator’s
                    starboard (right) is the stand-on vessel.
                    /$
                    /$/@Overtaking:/@ The vessel that is overtaking another vessel is the give-way vessel. The vessel being overtaken is the stand-on vessel.
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>4</number>
                <content>/+Safe Navigation on the Water/+
                    /$ /#3.4 Responsibilities Between Vessels/#
                    /$
                    /$/@If operating a power-driven vessel, you must give way to:/@
                    /$/- Any vessel not under command, such as an anchored or disabled vessel
                    /$/- Any vessel restricted in its ability to manoeuvre, such as a vessel towing, laying cable, or picking up navigation markers, or a
                    vessel constrained by its draft, such as a large ship in a channel
                    /$/- A vessel engaged in commercial fishing
                    /$/- A sailing vessel unless it is overtaking
                    /$
                    /$/@If operating a sailing vessel, you must give way to:/@
                    /$/- Any vessel not under command
                    /$/- Any vessel restricted in its ability to manoeuvre
                    /$/- A vessel engaged in commercial fishing
                    /$
                    /$/@If operating a vessel engaged in fishing, you must give way to:/@
                    /$/- Any vessel not under command
                    /$/- Any vessel restricted in its ability to manoeuvre
                    /$
                    /$/@If operating a paddlecraft, such as a canoe or kayak:/@
                    /$/- Keep a sharp lookout to avoid a collision since other vessel operators may not see you.
                    /$/- Use a whistle or other sound-signalling device to make other boaters aware of your presence. At night, also use a flashlight, lantern, or flare.
                    /$/- Paddle as close to shore as is safe, and avoid channels used by larger craft.
                    </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
    </course>
    <course>
        <name>Web Development</name>
        <code>103</code>
        <unit>
            <title>1</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+HTML5/+
                    /$ /#1.1 Intro/#
                    /$
                    /$HTML5 is a scripting language used to roughly layout elements on a webpage and can be used in correlation
                    with other scripting and web programming technologies. Below, you will see details and explanations on how to use
                    these elements and will be tested on them later.
                    /$
                    /$The first thing to know about html, is tags. Tags are how you indicate what type of element you are
                    using. Each tag must have a starting tag and ending tag.  Each
                    ending tag must start with a "/". The example below will print "Hello World" as a paragraph:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltp/gtHello World/lt/p/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+HTML5/+
                    /$ /#1.2 Comments/#
                    /$
                    /$Comments are a very useful tool to communicate to other programmers what the purpose of a certain
                    chunk of code is for. Comments are ignored no matter how many or what is written in them. These lines of
                    code are denoted using /lt!--/gt. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lt!--This is an example comment--/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>3</number>
                <content>/+HTML5/+
                    /$ /#1.3 Head and Body/#
                    /$
                    /$The head and body are the two basic children of an HTML program. In the head tag, things like the
                    title, such as at the top of this page/^s tab where it says "Web Programming", and styles for the page.
                    The body holds all of the text and media of the page spanning from the top of the page to the bottom.
                    For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lthtml/gt
                    /$/%    /lthead/gt
                    /$/%/%        /lttitle/gtWeb Programming/lt/title/gt
                    /$/%/%        /ltstyle/gt/lt/style/gt
                    /$/%    /lt/head/gt
                    /$/%    /ltbody/gt
                    /$/%/%        /lttext/gtHello World/lt/text/gt
                    /$/%    /lt/body/gt
                    /$/lt/html/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>4</number>
                <content>/+HTML5/+
                    /$ /#1.4 Paragraphs and Headings/#
                    /$
                    /$The paragraph element is denoted with a "p". This will seperate text from other text portions as
                    paragraphs in contrast to the "text" element which just concatenizes the text right after the last
                    character on the page. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltp/gtThis sample text will be displayed on its own/lt/p/gt/@
                    /$
                    /$Heading elements are denoted with an "h#" where the # sign is an integer between 1 and 6. The number
                    corresponds to the size and boldness of the font and 1 is the biggest while 6 is the smallest. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lth1/gtThis is the heading/lt/h1/gt
                    /$/lth3/gtThis is the paragraph corresponding to the header text which is slightly larger font than default and in bold/lt/h3/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>5</number>
                <content>/+HTML5/+
                    /$ /#1.5 Forms and Inputs/#
                    /$
                    /$Forms are used to assemble data and send or receive data to and from addresses. A form is needed for
                    inputs to function. As you can see below, "method" is set to post, meaning when the form is submitted,
                    the value of the text field will be sent to the address that is held in "action". There are different options
                    available for "method" and "action". For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltform method = "post" action = "data.htm"/gt
                    /$/%    /ltp/gt
                    /$/%/%        /ltinput name = "name" type = "text" size = "25" maxlength = "30"/gt
                    /$/%    /lt/p/gt
                    /$/lt/form/gt/@
                    /$
                    /$Text fields are used to collect user input in the form of a string. The "type" of the input element
                    must be set to "text", give the input a name in the "name" attribute as well as other attributes such as
                    "size" and "maxlength". For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltinput name = "textbox" type = "text" size = "25" maxlength = "30"/gt/@
                    /$
                    /$Check boxes are created by setting the "type" to "checkbox". For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltinput name = "checkbox" type = "checkbox"/gt/@
                    /$
                    /$Radio buttons are binary buttons that can be grouped together so that only one can be selected at one
                    time by having multiple radio buttons with the same name attribute while giving them a different string value.
                    These are created using the type "radio". For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltinput type = "radio" name = "radiobutton" value = "Option 1"/gt
                    /$/ltinput type = "radio" name = "radiobutton" value = "Option 2"/gt/@
                    /$
                    /$The submit type defines a button used to submit data from a form to a form handler. This is denoted
                    by setting "type" to "submit" and "value" set to the string written on the button. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltinput type = "submit" value = "Submit"/gt/@
                    /$
                    /$The reset type is a button that is used to clear all of the information the user has entered in the
                    form. Just like submit, the "type" needs to be set to "reset" and the "value" is where to put the string
                    for the button. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltinput type = "reset" value = "Clear"/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
        <unit>
            <title>2</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+CSS/+
                    /$ /#2.1 Intro/#
                    /$
                    /$CSS, short for Cascading Style Sheet, is a very useful tool for stylizing web pages. There are many
                    different ways to use the styles such as an external stylesheet that the html file links to or using in line
                    or embedded.
                    /$
                    /$In line styles are style attributes put directly after the declaration of the element which are terminated
                    by a colon and then followed by the value of the attribute and then a semicolon. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltp style = "font-size: 20; color: red;"/gt
                    /$/%    This is an example paragraph with font size 20 and a font color of red.
                    /$/lt/p/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+CSS/+
                    /$ /#2.2 Embedded Style Sheets/#
                    /$
                    /$Embedded style sheets function much like in line styles but they are declared in the document/^s
                    head section. The pre-existing styles of an element like "p" can be reset and totally altered as well
                    as creating a class of styles but prefixing the name of the class with a ".". When a class is applied to
                    an element, it adds the class/^s styles to the element unless that style already has a value, in which
                    case the pre-existing style is overwritten. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lthead/gt
                    /$/%    /ltstyle type = "text/css"/gt
                    /$/%/%            p {
                    /$/%/%/%                float: bottom;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-size: 30px;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-color: #8B0000;
                    /$/%/%/%                margin-left: 30px;
                    /$/%/%/%                margin-right: 30px;
                    /$/%/%            }
                    /$/%/%            .paragraph {
                    /$/%/%/%                font-size: 10px;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-color: #0000FF;
                    /$/%/%            }
                    /$/%    /lt/style/gt
                    /$/lt/head/gt
                    /$/ltbody/gt
                    /$/%    /ltp/gtThis text is size 30 in red/lt/p/gt
                    /$/%    /ltp class = "paragraph"/gtThis text is size 10 in blue/lt/p/gt
                    /$/lt/body/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>3</number>
                <content>/+CSS/+
                    /$ /#2.3 Font Styles/#
                    /$
                    /$There are many different options for fonts in CSS, there is font-family, font-size, font-weight, and font-color.
                    There are predetermined values for font-family, font-size is typically specified by an integer followed by a
                    "px", font-weight is the boldness of the font and font-color is typically specified with a hexadecimal
                    numbering system. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lthead/gt
                    /$/%    /ltstyle type = "text/css"/gt
                    /$/%/%            .paragraph {
                    /$/%/%/%                font-size: 10px;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-color: #0000FF;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-family: arial, sans-serif;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-weight: bold;
                    /$/%/%            }
                    /$/%    /lt/style/gt
                    /$/lt/head/gt/@
                    /$
                    /$Text decoration defines underline, overline, line-through, blink, and none. These are fairly
                    straight forward. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lthead/gt
                    /$/%    /ltstyle type = "text/css"/gt
                    /$/%/%            .paragraph {
                    /$/%/%/%                font-size: 10px;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-color: #0000FF;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-family: arial, sans-serif;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-weight: bold;
                    /$/%/%/%                text-decoration: underline;
                    /$/%/%            }
                    /$/%    /lt/style/gt
                    /$/lt/head/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>4</number>
                <content>/+CSS/+
                    /$ /#2.4 Margins/#
                    /$
                    /$Margins are very useful for a pleasant appearance of a web page. This attribute is used to provide a
                    minimum amount of space from other elements on the web page measured in pixels. Each direction of top, down,
                    right, left has its own margin specification. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lthead/gt
                    /$/%    /ltstyle type = "text/css"/gt
                    /$/%/%            .paragraph {
                    /$/%/%/%                font-size: 10px;
                    /$/%/%/%                margin-top: 30px;
                    /$/%/%/%                margin-down: 30px;
                    /$/%/%/%                margin-right: 30px;
                    /$/%/%/%                margin-left: 30px;
                    /$/%/%            }
                    /$/%/%            /* This makes a 30px padding around the whole of the p element*/
                    /$/%    /lt/style/gt
                    /$/lt/head/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>5</number>
                <content>/+CSS/+
                    /$ /#2.5 External Style Sheets/#
                    /$
                    /$External stylesheets are a stylesheet that is not embedded or in-line. These are CSS files stored in
                    somewhere seperate from the web page. Using the link element, we can link the html file and css file
                    together by specifying 'rel' (short for relationship) to be "stylesheet", 'type' set to "text/css" to
                    indicate the contents are written in CSS, and 'href' containing the location of the stylesheet.
                    For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lthead/gt
                    /$    /ltlink rel = "stylesheet" type = "text/css" href = "style.css"/gt
                    /$/lt/head/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>6</number>
                <content>/+CSS/+
                    /$ /#2.6 CSS Comments/#
                    /$
                    /$Comments in CSS are different than those in HTML. Comments in CSS are started with "/*" and end with
                    "*/", this means that everything after "/*" is ignored until "*/". For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lthead/gt
                    /$/%    /ltstyle type = "text/css"/gt
                    /$/%/%            /* All of this text is going to be ignored, as well as the p class
                    /$/%/%            p {
                    /$/%/%/%                float: bottom;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-size: 30px;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-color: #8B0000;
                    /$/%/%/%                margin-left: 30px;
                    /$/%/%/%                margin-right: 30px;
                    /$/%/%            }
                    /$/%/%            */
                    /$/%/%            .paragraph {
                    /$/%/%/%                font-size: 10px;
                    /$/%/%/%                font-color: #0000FF;
                    /$/%/%            }
                    /$/%    /lt/style/gt
                    /$/lt/head/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
        <unit>
            <title>3</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+JavaScript/+
                    /$ /#3.1 Intro/#
                    /$
                    /$This tutorial is under the assumption that you already have a working knowledge of Java but want to learn how to use JavaScript
                    in an HTML format. JavaScript can be implemented in HTML5 to add additional functionality to web pages using a traditional
                    programming language and the versatility that javaScript can offer that HTML5 can/^t.
                    /$
                    /$The first thing to know is how to add a script to HTML. The script is inserted using the "script"
                    element and specifying the "type" as "text/javascript". Inside the element you can then
                    write in JavaScript. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lthtml/gt
                    /$/%    /lthead/gt
                    /$/%/%        /lttitle/gtJavaScript Example/lt/title/gt
                    /$/%/%        /ltscript type = "text/javascript"/gt
                    /$/%/%/%            document.writeln("");
                    /$/%/%        /lt/script/gt
                    /$/%    /lt/head/gt
                    /$/lt/html/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+JavaScript/+
                    /$ /#3.2 Strings/#
                    /$
                    /$Writing strings to the web page using JavaScript uses the writeln() function of the document class.
                    What this does is writes the contents of the parantheses to the document, but if the html line wouldn/^t
                    print anything to the web page if it was inserted on it/^s own then it won/^t print in JavaScript. For example
                    if the writeln() method had "This is an example string" written in it, then it wouldn/^t print that to the
                    screen. However, if it had "/ltp/gtThis is an example string/lt/p/gt" it would work. It would look like this:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltscript type = "text/javascript"/gt
                    /$/%    document.writeln("/ltp/gtThis is an example string/lt/p/gt");
                    /$/lt/script/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>3</number>
                <content>/+JavaScript/+
                    /$ /#3.3 Alerts/#
                    /$
                    /$Alerts are a useful way to get a user/^s attention an deliver some information to them. An alert is a
                    little popup window at the top of the screen that displays a message from the server and has an OK button.
                    To send an alert, use the alert method in the window class sending the message as the parameter. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltscript type = "text/javascript"/gt
                    /$/%    window.alert("This is the alert message\nI am alerting the user!");
                    /$/lt/script/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>4</number>
                <content>/+JavaScript/+
                    /$ /#3.4 Escape Sequences/#
                    /$
                    /$Escape sequences are essentially special characters in JavaScript. Since quotation marks are used
                    in the syntax when writing a string, we need a way to indicate that we want to write an actual single
                    quote to the document rather than finishing the string. Other escape sequences are tabs and new lines.
                    Here is a list of them:
                    /$
                    /$\\\\/@n - New line
                    /$\\\\t - Tab
                    /$\\\\ - Backslash
                    /$\\\\" - Double Quote
                    /$\\\\/^ - Single Quote/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>5</number>
                <content>/+JavaScript/+
                    /$ /#3.5 Prompts/#
                    /$
                    /$Prompting the user in JavaScript to get some information to be used later is as simple as declaring
                    a variable in the script, saving the result of the prompt to that variable and then using the vairable. A
                    variable can hold any data type and is declared with "var" followed by a "=" and then the name of the
                    variable. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltscript type = "text/javascript"/gt
                    /$/%    var = food;
                    /$
                    /$/%    food = window.prompt("What is your favorite food?");
                    /$
                    /$/%    document.writeln("/ltp/gtYour favorite food is " + food + "./lt/p/gt");
                    /$/lt/script/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>6</number>
                <content>/+JavaScript/+
                    /$ /#3.6 Referring to HTML Attributes/#
                    /$
                    /$To refer and listen to elements in html such as buttons or images through JavaScript, there needs to be
                    an id given to that element. After that, in JavaScript, one can set a local variable to have a reference to
                    that element by using the getElementById() method in the document class. Once this has been done, the
                    setAttribute() method can be used to change something about that element. Also, to modify the contents
                    of the element, use the innerHTML variable of the getElementById() method of the document class. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lthtml/gt
                    /$/%    /lthead/gt
                    /$/%/%        /lttitle/gtJavaScript Example/lt/title/gt
                    /$/%/%        /ltscript type = "text/javascript"/gt
                    /$/%/%/%            var message = document.getElementById("exampleMessage");
                    /$
                    /$/%/%/%            message.setAttribute("style", "font-size: 20px;");
                    /$/%/%/%            message.innerHTML = "The new Message";
                    /$/%/%        /lt/script/gt
                    /$/%    /lt/head/gt
                    /$/%    /ltbody/gt
                    /$/%/%        /ltp id = "exampleMessage"/gtThis text is getting to changed to font size 20/lt/p/gt
                    /$/%    /lt/body/gt
                    /$/lt/html/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>7</number>
                <content>/+JavaScript/+
                    /$ /#3.7 Externally Linked/#
                    /$
                    /$It is possible to have an external JavaScript linked to the HTML file. The "script" element is still
                    used, however, there needs to be a source attribute denoted with "src" and setting it equal to the path
                    of the JavaScript file. Once this is in place, all of the JavaScript can be written in the .js file.
                    /$
                    /$/@/lthead/gt
                    /$/%    /lttitle/gtJavaScript Example/lt/title/gt
                    /$/%    /ltscript src = "file.js"/gt/lt/script/gt
                    /$/lt/head/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>8</number>
                <content>/+JavaScript/+
                    /$ /#3.8 Event Handling/#
                    /$
                    /$There are a number of different ways to handle events in JavaScript. Onload is a handler that when
                    the page loads, it will execute the function that onload was set to. Cursor listeners need a canvas
                    in the document to refer to in order to listen to a mouse action, and the addEventListener() function can
                    be used to listen to a certain action and then call a function in that case. addEventListener can be
                    used on many other elements as well, use them in the same way below but for other elements. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/lthead/gt
                    /$/%    /lttitle/gtJavaScript Example/lt/title/gt
                    /$/%    /ltscript/gt
                    /$/%/%    document.onload = "start()";
                    /$/%/%    document.getElementById("canvas").addEventListener("mousemove", processMouseMove, false);
                    /$
                    /$/%/%    function start(){
                    /$/%/%/%        //Do something
                    /$/%/%    }
                    /$
                    /$/%/%    function processMouseMove( e ){
                    /$/%/%/%        //Process mouse
                    /$/%/%    }
                    /$/%    /lt/script/gt
                    /$/lt/head/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
        <unit>
            <title>4</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+XML/+
                    /$ /#4.1 Intro/#
                    /$
                    /$XML is a widespread, portable tool for data storage and exchange. It, similarily to HTML5, uses tags
                    to construct a tree of data starting with one root element. Each element must have a closing tag before the
                    closing tag of it/^s parent.
                    /$
                    /$In XML there are a selection of special characters that cannot be typed in as string or character
                    data as the parser will think it is part of the syntax of the language. Codes must be used to get the
                    desired symbol to display after the file has been parsed. These are denoted with an "/=", followed
                    by a number or series of letters to get the desired symbol and then a semicolon, this means that now "/="
                    needs to have it/^s own code. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/=  - /=amp;
                    /$/lt  - /=lt;
                    /$/gt  - /=gt;
                    /$"  - /=quot;
                    /$/^  - /=apos;/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+XML/+
                    /$ /#4.2 Moving Through XML File/#
                    /$
                    /$To access the data in an XML file from an XSL file you will need to use "value-of", "for-each",
                    and "sort". Using "value-of" will return the value of the path that is given to the "select" attribute.
                    Using "for-each" will run a loop for every instance of the element specified in the "select" attribute.
                    Using "sort" in "for-each" will execute the loop in a sorted manner sorting by the element specified
                    in the "select" attribute. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@/ltxml/gt
                    /$/%    /ltdata/gt
                    /$/%/%        /ltcd/gt
                    /$/%/%/%            /lttitle/gtEye of the Tiger/lt/title/gt
                    /$/%/%/%            /ltartist/gtSurvivor/lt/artist/gt
                    /$/%/%        /lt/cd/gt
                    /$/%/%        /ltcd/gt
                    /$/%/%/%            /lttitle/gtThunderstruck/lt/title/gt
                    /$/%/%/%            /ltartist/gtAC/DC/lt/artist/gt
                    /$/%/%        /lt/cd/gt
                    /$/%    /lt/data/gt
                    /$/lt/xml/gt
                    /$/ltxsl/gt
                    /$/%    /lthtml/gt
                    /$/%/%        /lt!--This will display Thunderstruck first followed by Eye of the Tiger--/gt
                    /$/%/%        /ltxsl:for-each select = "data/cd"/gt
                    /$/%/%/%            /ltxsl:sort select = "artist"/gt
                    /$/%/%/%            /lth2/gt/ltxsl:value-of select = "title"/gt/lt/h2/gt
                    /$/%/%/%            /lth4/gt/ltxsl:value-of select = "artist"/gt/lt/h4/gt
                    /$/%/%        /lt/xsl:for-each/gt
                    /$/%    /lt/html/gt
                    /$/lt/xsl/gt/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
        <unit>
            <title>5</title>
            <subUnit>
                <number>1</number>
                <content>/+Ajax/+
                    /$ /#4.1 Intro/#
                    /$
                    /$Ajax is a technology that uses XML and JSON to speed up the client-side to server-side communication
                    and experience. In traditional web applications the web page is stalled until the server has processed the
                    data, with Ajax, the web page and processing run in parallel to each other letting the user continue to
                    interact with the page.
                    /$
                    /$The JavaScript side of communicating to the server uses variables and functions attached to the
                    XMLHttpRequest object such as, open(), send(), and responseText. First, the program must open a request,
                    then send the request, wait for the response and then retrieve the data that has been put in responseText.
                    For example, this is what that code would look like:
                    /$
                    /$/@var link = new XMLHttpRequest();
                    /$
                    /$link.open("GET", "data.xml", true);
                    /$link.send(null);
                    /$
                    /$document.getElementById("dataDestination").innerHTML = link.responseText;/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>2</number>
                <content>/+Ajax/+
                    /$ /#4.2 Detecting the Return of Data/#
                    /$
                    /$The best way to know when to know the data has been back from the server is to place an event
                    listener on it to detect "readystatechange" and to take action upon that change. Also, we should check
                    readyState to make sure that its value is 4 due to the fact that that means the request was successful. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@var link = new XMLHttpRequest();
                    /$
                    /$link.open("GET", "data.xml", true);
                    /$link.send(null);
                    /$
                    /$link.addEventListener("readystatechange", ready, false);
                    /$
                    /$function ready(){
                    /$/%    if(link.readyState == 4){
                    /$/%/%        document.getElementById("dataDestination").innerHTML = link.responseText;
                    /$/%    }
                    /$}/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
            <subUnit>
                <number>3</number>
                <content>/+Ajax/+
                    /$ /#4.3 Error Catching/#
                    /$
                    /$It is good programming practice to nestle these requests in a try catch block to avoid critical errors. For example:
                    /$
                    /$/@try{
                    /$/%    var link = new XMLHttpRequest();
                    /$
                    /$/%    link.open("GET", "data.xml", true);
                    /$/%    link.send(null);
                    /$}catch(exception){
                    /$/%    alert("Request Failed");
                    /$}/@
                </content>
            </subUnit>
        </unit>
    </course>
</xml>
